# Didem Uzuncaova

- <sup>♠</sup> Bothell, WA
- 5123632293

## **SUMMARY**

I am a software test engineer who is experienced in application compatibility testing and software localization testing; knowledgeable in SDLC (software development life cycle), executing test plans, tracking and logging defects in Mercury Quality Center and Visual Studio; worked on projects in Windows, Bing and Microsoft Sync; completed certificate program on quality assurance / software testing; motivated, hard working and self- driven individual with excellent social skills.

#### **SKILLS**

- Testing
- Localization
- Data Analysis
- Linguistic tester- Turkish
- TFS
- Compatibility Testing
- Windows 8
- Bug Tracking
- Manual Testing
- Test Case Generation

- Quality Assurance
- SDLC
- Software Testing
- Visual Studio
- Web Applications
- Windows 7
- Windows 8.1
- Regression Testing
- Test Cases
- windows 10

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Microsoft

03 / 2015 - Present

Software Test Engineer - Wipro

- Software Tester of the Application Compatibility team targeting Windows 10.
- · Testing Windows applications using different scenarios
- Validating on different OS targets (OS upgrades, updates and builds) and machine architectures
- Writing defect reports, working with development teams to resolve / close defects
- · Managing test machines and deployments

#### Microsoft

01 / 2014 - 09 / 2014

Data Analyst

- Query Judgment: Judging relevancy of search results based on query terms
- Categorization: Classify search terms based on a database of set categories
- Error Reduction Work: Proofreading business names, descriptions, and images.
- Business Matching: Grouping same businesses received from various sources

## Microsoft

04 / 2013 - 06 / 2013

Software Localization Tester - Turkish

- Verification of linguistic accuracy and resource attributes
- Checking typographical errors
- Identifying and documenting bugs clearly in a bug database.
- · Verifying that bugs have been fixed and implemented correctly

**uTest** 09 / 2014 - 11 / 2014

Freelance Software Tester

Participate in testing cycles for web and mobile applications, reviewing requirements, test plan documentation, conduct exploratory testing of mobile/desktop applications, bug reporting and tracking using uTest platforms, complete regression testing, and fix verification.

### Page Ahead Children's Literacy Program

03 / 2011 - 05 / 2011

Office Assistant (Volunteering position)

**Toprakbank** 

09 / 1995 - 02 / 2001

Global Trade Services

Central Operations Department (1999-2001) Global Trade / Foreign Exchange, Import/ Export, Assistant Manager Izmit Branch (1997-1999) Bank Wire Transfer Kadikoy Branch, Istanbul (1995-1997) Bank Teller

#### **EDUCATION**

## **QA101 Software Testing, Quality Assurance**

2014 - 2014

The QA101 course is an intensive Software Testing study program where student are trained according to college-level curricula, and are expected to submit homework assignments weekly. This course provides a full understanding of the modern Software Development Life Cycle. -Waterfall/ Agile-Scrum/ Spiral -Testing methods and Test Case Writing -Mercury Quality Center -Defect logging, design and management

# **Istanbul University**

1991 - 1993

Associate's degree, Tourism and Travel Services Management

# LANGUAGES

• English ( Professional working proficiency )

• Turkish ( Native or bilingual proficiency )